Finding Aid for James B. Griffin Papers 1922-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Writings and Publications, 1930-1997
  - By Others
    - Hall, Robert L.
      - Papers, 1976-1981 (Box 75)
    - Halsey, John R.
      - Papers, 1968-1980 (Box 75)
    - Hard, Robert A.
      - "The Relation of Eastern Archaeology to Michigan,", 1955 (Box 75)
        (student paper)
    - Harn, Alan D.
      - "The Larson Community: A Mississippian Settlement System in the Spoon River Area of Illinois,", 1975 (Box 75)
      - "Subsistence, Seasonality and Site Function at Upland Camps in the Larson Community: A View From the Other End of the Telescope,", 1983 (Box 75)
    - Harris, Suzanne
      - "Cultural Change on the Central Plains A.D. 1000-1700,", 1972 (Box 75)
        (doctoral paper)
      - Papers, 1969-1971 (Box 75)
    - Hecker, Thad C.
      - "Stratigraphy at the Lockport Site,", 1947 (Box 75)
      - "Non-Agricultural Pottery-Makers of the Northern Great Plains,", 1948 (Box 75)
    - Heilman, James M. and Hoefer, Roger R.
      - "Possible Astronomical Alignments in a Fort Ancient Settlement at the Incinerator Site in Dayton, Ohio,", 1980 (Box 75)
    - Hermann, Barbara
      - "The Artifacts from the Schwartz and Orr Sites, An Analysis of Adena Culture,", 1945 (Box 75)
    - Hofman, Jack L.
      - "The Twenhefel Site as Reflected by Extant Literature: An Annotated Bibliography,", 1979 (Box 75)
    - Hole, Frank
      - Papers, 1971; undated (Box 75)
    - Hoopes, John W.
      - "The Chronology and Relationships of the Earliest Ceramic Complexes in the New World 6000-1500 B.C." (with Griffin's comments), 1992 (Box 75)
    - Hunston, Jeffrey R.
      - Yukon Territory Papers, 1977 (Box 76)
    - Hurley, William M.
      - Ceramic Class and Attribute List (with N. Wagner), 1972 (Box 76)
      - Papers, 1967-1973 (Box 76)
    - Ikawa-Smith, Fumiko
      - Papers Related to Japanese Paleolithic, 1973-1974 (Box 76)
    - Irwin-Williams, Cynthia
      - "The Elementary Southwestern Culture: The Configuration of Late Preceramic Development in the Southwestern United States,", 1965 (Box 76)
    - Jackson, H. Edwin
      - Papers, 1982-1994 (Box 76)
    - Jelinek, Arthur J.
      - "The Lower Paleolithic: Current Evidence and Interpretations,", 1977 (Box 76)
    - Jenkins, Ned J.
      - "The Gulf Tradition and Hopewellian Ceramics,", 1982 (Box 76)
    - Johnson, Gregory
      - "Diyala Basin: Ed. I-III Locational Analysis,", 1970 (Box 76)
      - Papers, 1974-1985 (Box 76)
    - Johnson, W.C.
      - "The Campbell Farm Site (36FA26) and Monongahela: A Preliminary Examination and Assessment,", 1981 (Box 76)
    - Kay, Marvin
      - Papers Related to Phillips, Spring 1978 (Box 76)
    - Kay, Marvin and Johnson, Alfred E.
      - "Havana Tradition Chronology of Central Missouri,", undated (Box 76)
    - Kingsley, Robert G.
      - "Hopewell Middle Woodland Settlement Systems and Cultural Dynamics in Southern Michigan,", 1980 (Box 76)
      - "An Analysis of the Mortuary Practices at the Norton Mounds Site,", 1981 (Box 76)
    - Kleinsasser, Glenn
      - "Report on the Excavations at the Fort Berthold Indian Village Site,", 1951 (Box 76)
    - Knight, Vernon J.
      - "The Expeditions of Clarence B. Moore to Moundville in 1905 and 1906,", 1995 (Box 76)
    - Koschik, Wilma
      - "A Nutritional Analysis of the Tehuacan Valley Sequence,", undated (Box 76)
      - Papers, undated (Box 76)
    - Kurland, Anthony
      - "An Analytical History of the Archaeological Concept of Tradition,", 1975 (Box 76)
    - Larson, Lewis H.
      - "An Examination of the Significance of a Turtle Shell Hair Pin from Etowah,", 1951-1957 (Box 76)
      - Papers, undated (Box 76)
    - Lee, J.R.
      - Jesuit Relations and Climate, undated (Box 76)
    - Lee, Thomas E.
      - "Archeological Sequences in Southern Ontario and New York State," (student paper), 1950 (Box 76)
    - Lewis, R. Barry and Mackin, Lynne M.
      - "The Adams Site Ceramic Assemblage in Regional Perspective,", undated (Box 76)
    - Linton, Ralph
      - "North American Cooking Pots" (with Griffin's comments), 1943 (Box 76)
    - Lovis, William
      - "A Numerical Taxonomic Analysis of Changing Woodland Site Location Strategies on an Interior Lake Chain,", 1978 (Box 76)
    - Low, Charles F.
      - "Archaeological Explorations Near Madisonville, Ohio, Part II, September 1 to December 8, 1879" (Box 76)
    - Luedtke, Barbara
      - Papers (includes portions of thesis) (Box 76)
    - Macdonald, William K.
      - "Adena: Still Seeking an Identity,", 1982 (Box 76)
    - MacNeish, Richard S.
      - Faulkner Site, 1945-1947 (Box 76)
      - "Summary of Archaeological Investigations in Southeastern Manitoba,", 1955 (Box 76)
      - Survey of Canadian Archaeology, 1952 (Box 76)
    - Malouf, Richard T.
      - "Camas and the Flathead Indians of Montana,", 1971 (Box 76)
      - Chapter on Chickasaw for doctoral dissertation, 1974 (Box 76)
      - Papers, 1970-1971 (Box 76)
    - Markman, Charles W.
      - "Above the American Bottom: The Late Woodland-Mississippian Transition in Northeastern Illinois,", 1986 (Box 76)
    - Marquardt, William H. and Watson, Patty Jo
      - Papers on Green River, Kentucky Shell Mound Project, 1974-1976 (Box 76)
    - Marshall, James A.
      - "American Indian Geometry,", undated (Box 77)
    - Mason, Ronald J.
      - "Progress Report on Lawrence University Excavations at Rock Island State Park, Door County, Wisconsin,", 1971-1973 (Box 77)
      - "Early Man and the Age of the Champlain Sea,", 1959 (Box 77)
    - Matson, Frederick R.
      - "Notes on the Indian Pottery Obtained Near Imlay City, Michigan,", 1936 (Box 77)
      - "A Study of the Restoration and Examination of Copper and Bronze,", 1938 (Box 77)
    - McGimsey, Charles R., III
      - "Headwaters, or How the Federal Government Became Involved in Archaeology in the Mid-South and Elsewhere at WWII,", circa 1997 (Box 77)
    - McGregor, John C.
      - Havana Pottery, undated (Box 77)
    - McNett, Charles W., Marshall, Sydne B., and McDowell, Ellis E.
      - "Second Season of the Upper Delaware Valley Early Man Project,", 1975 (Box 77)
    - Meltzer, David J. and Sturtevant, William C.
      - "The Holly Oak Shell Game: An Historic Archaeological Fraud," [1983] (Box 77)
    - Milner, George
      - Papers, 1985-1992 (Box 77)
    - Morse, Dan F.
      - "A Preliminary Report on 9-Go-507: The Williams Site, Gordon C., Georgia" (with Phyllis Morse), 1960 (Box 77)
      - "The Penetration of Northeast Arkansas by Mississippian Culture,", 1975 (Box 77)
    - Morse, Phyllis
      - "Parkin: The 1978-79 Archeological Investigation of a Cross County, Arkansas Site,", 1979 (Box 77)
    - Muller, Jon
      - "The Kincaid Site and Its Environs" (with Frank Rackerby and Phil C. Weigand), 1970 (Box 77)
      - "The Southern Cult, 1984 (Box 77)
    - Munson, Patrick J.
      - "Changes in and Relationships of Subsistence, Settlement, and Population in the Central Illinois River Valley,", 1976 (Box 77)
    - Murphy, James L.
      - "Archaeology of the Plains Area,", 1965 (Box 77)
    - Neumann, Georg K.
      - "Crania from the Hagan Mound," [1941] (Box 77)
    - Noble, W.C.
      - "Some Social Implications of the Iroquois 'In Situ' Theory,", 1974 (Box 77)
    - O'Leary, Timothy J. (compiler)
      - "A Preliminary Bibliography of the Archaeology of Western Canada,", undated (Box 77)
    - Orr, Kenneth G.
      - "A Comparison of the Eufaula Mound and the Spiro Mounds,", 1942 (Box 77)
      - "Summary Statements of the Present Status of Archaeological Research in the Starved Rock Area, La Salle County, Illinois,", 1949 (Box 77)
    - Orser, Charles E. (compiler)
      - "Annotated Bibliography of Archaeological Contract Surveys Conducted in Michigan from 1970 through 1979,", 1984 (Box 77)
    - Parsons, Jeffrey R.
      - Papers, 1969-1974; 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Peebles, Christopher
      - "Paradise Lost, Strayed, and Stolen: Prehistoric Social Devolution in the Southeast,", 1983 (Box 78)
      - Moundville Papers, 1970-1985; 4 folders (Box 78)
      - Papers, 1983-1987 (Box 78)
    - Perino, Gregory H.
      - "Excavation of the Banks Site,", 1959 (Box 78)
      - "Filed Teeth Discoveries in the Cahokia Area After 1950,", 1966 (Box 78)
    - Pewe, Troy L.
      - "Brief Review of Pleistocene Events and Climatic Changes in Alaska,", 1953 (Box 78)
    - Pickenpaugh, Thomas E.
      - "Brokaw Village (33BL-6): An Example of Late Prehistoric Native American Civil Engineering,", 1985-1986 (Box 78)
    - Pires-Ferreira, Jane Wheeler
      - Papers, 1972; 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Pratt, Peter P.
      - Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 78)
    - Price, James E.
      - "Emergence and Development of Mississippian Traditions in the Central Mississippi Valley,", 1973 (Box 78)
      - "Mississippian Settlement Systems of the Central Mississippi Valley,", 1974 (Box 78)
      - Papers, 1973 (Box 78)
    - Prufer, Olaf H., Seeman, Mark F., and Mensforth, Robert P.
      - "The Lukens Cache: A Ceremonial Offering from Ohio,", 1982 (Box 78)
        (includes slides)
    - Purrington, Burton L.
      - "A Reappraisal of the C&O Mounds and Adena Occupation of the Eastern Kentucky Mountains,", 1972 (Box 78)
    - Putnam, F.W.
      - "Report on the Excavations at the Lindsley Site,", 1878 (Box 78)
        (notes from Eleventh Annual Report of the Peabody Museum of American Archaeology and Ethnology)
    - Redding, Richard
      - Papers, 1970s (Box 78)
    - Richardson, James B., III
      - Papers on Bottle Gourd Origins, 1964 (Box 78)
    - Ridley, Frank
      - Papers on the Fallis Site, 1950 (Box 78)
    - Riley, Tom
      - Papers, 1970s (Box 78)
    - Robbins, Maurice
      - Progress Reports on Wapanucket #8, 1961-1962 (Box 78)
    - Ruhl, Katharine C.
      - "A Seriation of Copper Earspools from Ohio Hopewell Sites,", 1990 (Box 79)
    - Sackett, Jim
      - Papers (Box 79)
    - Salzer, Robert J.
      - "Preceramic Occupations in North-Central Wisconsin,", 1969 (Box 79)
    - Saxe, Arthur A.
      - "Social Dimensions of Mortuary Practices in a Mesolithic Population from Wadi Halfa, Sudan,", 1966 (Box 79)
    - Schambach, Frank
      - "A Review of Dragoo, Don W.: Mounds for the Dead: An Analysis of the Adena Culture,", 1965 (Box 79)
    - Schmitt, Karl
      - "Patawomeke: An Historic Algonkian Site,", 1942 (Box 79)
    - Schroeder, David L. and Clapp, Katharine P.
      - "North-American Prehistoric Copper Metallurgy,", 1965 (Box 79)
    - Scully, Edward
      - "An Appraisal and Application of the Binomial Projectile Point Classification,", undated (Box 79)
    - Shott, Michael
      - Manuscript About Radiocarbon Dating and the Childers Site, 1990 (Box 79)
      - "Paleo-Indian Technological Organization and Settlement Mobility in the Great Lakes Region,", 1983 (Box 79)
    - Smail, William
      - "Some Early Projectile Points from the St. Louis Area,", 1951 (Box 79)
    - Smith, Bruce D.
      - "Mississippian Elites and Solar Alignments -- A Reflection of Managerial Necessity, or Levers of Social Inequality,", 1991 (Box 79)
      - Papers, 1973-1979; 2 folders (Box 79)
    - Smith, Carlyle S.
      - "A Winter Village on Bull Creek, South Dakota,", 1954 (Box 79)
    - Smith, Cyril Stanley
      - "Metallographic Study of Early Artifacts Made from Native Copper,", 1965 (Box 79)
    - Smith, Hale G.
      - "Two Archaeological Sites in Brevard County, Florida,", 1948 (Box 79)
    - Speth, John D.
      - "Some Preliminary Observations on Fracture in Brittle Solids,", 1969 (Box 79)
    - Springer, James H.
      - Papers, 1975-1979 (Box 79)
    - Steinbring, Jack
      - Papers Related to Old Copper in Manitoba, 1966 (Box 79)
    - Steponaitis, Vincas
      - Papers, 1979-1980 (Box 79)
        (includes drafts of dissertation chapters)
    - Stoltman, James B.
      - "Ancient Peoples of the Upper Mississippi Valley,", 1983 (Box 79)
    - Stothers, David M.
      - "The Princess Point Complex,", 1971 (Box 79)
      - Western Lake Erie Basin Papers (some with David S. Brose), 1973-1981; 2 folders (Box 79)
    - Struever, Stuart
      - "Flotation Techniques for the Recovery of Small-Scale Archaeological Remains,", circa 1960 (Box 79)
      - "Some Thoughts on the Illinois Valley Archaeological Program 20 Years Later,", 1982 (Box 79)
    - Stuart, Gene
      - "The Eastern Woodlands" (with Griffin's comments), 1987 (Box 79)
    - Terra, Helmut de
      - "Fossil Man in Mexico and the Geophysical Aid in the Discovery,", 1947 (Box 79)
    - Theler, James L. and Dalbey, Timothy S.
      - "Chert Utilization at the Ferris Site, 33Ct31, an Early Archaic Camp in Southwestern Ohio,", 1974 (Box 79)
    - Trinkley, Michael
      - "A Typology of Thom's Creek Pottery for the South Carolina Coast,", 1976 (Box 79)
    - Tuck, James A.
      - "The 'Archaic Stage' in the New World,", undated (Box 79)
      - Manuscript on Maritime Archaic, 1975 (Box 79)
    - Vickery, Kent
      - Papers, 1969-1983 (Box 79)
    - Von Stokar, Walter
      - "Prehistoric Organic Remains,", 1938 (Box 79)
        (translated by J.F.S. Stone)
    - Walthall, John A.
      - "Galena and Aboriginal Trade in Eastern North America,", 1980 (Box 79)
    - Ward, H. Trawick
      - "Tribes and Traders: Contact and Change on the North Carolina Piedmont,", 1992 (Box 80)
    - Webb, Malcolm C.
      - Papers, 1967-1970 (Box 80)
    - Wedel, Mildred Mott
      - Oneota Trait List, 1942 (Box 80)
    - Welch, Paul D.
      - "Mississippian Occupations at Shiloh and Savannah, Tennessee,", 1996 (Box 80)
    - Wetterstrom, Wilma
      - Papers, 1975-1981 (Box 80)
    - Whallon, Robert
      - Papers, 1971-1974; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Whatley, Bonnie L. and Asch, Nancy B.
      - Woodland Subsistence: Implications for Demographic and Nutritional Studies,", 1975 (Box 80)
    - Wheeler, Richard P.
      - "A Check-List of Middle Missouri Pottery Wares, Types, and Subtypes,", 1954-1955 (Box 80)
    - Whiteford, Andrew H.
      - "Description for Artifact Analysis," [1947] (Box 80)
    - Wilford, Lloyd A.
      - Minnesota Pottery, undated (Box 80)
    - Wilkinson, Richard G.
      - Papers, 1965-1966 (Box 80)
    - Williams, Stephen
      - Papers, 1995-1996 (Box 80)
    - Wilmsen, Edwin N.
      - "Interaction, Spacing Behavior and the Organization of Hunting Bands,", 1972 (Box 80)
    - Witthoft, John
      - Papers, 1951-1967 (Box 80)
    - Wobst, H. Martin
      - Papers on French Pleistocene, 1966 (Box 80)
    - Wood, W. Raymond
      - "Pottery Types from the Sheyenne-Cheyenne Site, North Dakota,", 1957 (Box 80)
    - Wright, Henry T.
      - Papers, 1960s-1970s (Box 80)
    - Yarnell, Richard A. and Watson, Patty Jo
      - "The Prehistoric Utilization of Salts Cave, Kentucky,", 1967 (Box 80)
- Hopewell, 1938-1992
  The Hopewell series, 1938-1992 (1.25 linear feet), contains research files on Hopewell culture, a network of beliefs and practices among different Native American groups over much of eastern North America and one of Griffin's major areas of interest. Many of these files seem to have been compiled as research for a book-length manuscript on the Ohio Hopewell that Griffin, along with N'omi Greber, worked on for a number years, but apparently never completed. While this series represents a significant accumulation of Griffin's research on Hopewell, other writings, research files, and correspondence about this topic are located throughout the papers.
  - Hopewell Architecture, 1983-1984 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Environment of Ohio, 1980 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Exotic Materials and Trade, 1967-1992 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Foods, 1987-1989 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Group, 1925 (Box 81)
    (photocopies of field notes H.C. Shetrone)
  - Hopewell Mounds Collection in the Peabody Museum, 1980 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Obsidian and Other Trade, 1968-1980; 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Obsidian Studies, 1987 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Site Catalog (Field Museum), 1984 (Box 81)
  - Hopewell Slide Lists, 1973-1980 (Box 81)
  - Hopewellian in Indiana, 1941 (Box 81)
  - Hopewellian Trait List, circa 1938-1950 (Box 81)
  - Notes on the Mounds, 1891-1892 (Box 81)
    (photocopies of field notes by Warren K. Moorehead)
  - Ohio Hopewell Bibliography, undated (Box 81)
  - Ohio Hopewell Survey, 1985 (Box 81)
  - Pottery from Ohio Hopewell Sites, 1940s (Box 81)
  - Problems in the Interpretation of Hopewellian Culture, 1957 (Box 81)
  - Sites
    - Clark County, Ohio, 1981 (Box 81)
    - Drew Cemetery, Ohio, 1983 (Box 81)
    - Edwin Harness Mound, Ross County, Ohio (includes photos), 1978-1979 (Box 81)
    - Fort Ancient, 1984-1986 (Box 81)
    - GE Mound, Posey County, Indiana, 1992 (Box 81)
    - Harding County, Ohio, 1983-1992 (Box 81)
    - Hopeton Works, Ross County, Ohio, 1976 (Box 81)
    - Marietta, Ohio and Muskingum Hopewell, 1983 (Box 81)
    - Marietta Excavations, 1990 (Box 81)
    - Marion County, Kentucky, 1985-1986 (Box 81)
      (includes slides and photos)
    - Miami, Ohio, undated (Box 81)
    - Miami Fort, 1965-1967 (Box 81)
    - Porter Mound, Ross County, Ohio, undated (Box 82)
    - Porter Mound Textile Report, 1986 (Box 82)
    - Todd's Mound, Ohio, 1981-1982 (Box 82)
    - Warren County, Ohio, 1984 (Box 82)
  - Squier and Davis Collection
    - 1971-1988 (Box 82)
    - Undated (Box 82)
    - Photos (Box 82)
  - The Hopewell (correspondence and research regarding book-length manuscript), 1976-1985 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1970s (Box 82)
    - 1980s, 2 folders (Box 82)
- Topical Files, 1929-1991
  While the majority of information on Griffin's research and activities can be found in other series within these papers, the Topical Files series, 1929-1991 (5.5 linear feet), contains correspondence, reports, reviews, and research files related to select topics, and is divided into seven subseries: Archaeological Subject Files, Ceramics Research, Consulting, Grant Proposals and Projects, Neutron Activation Analysis, Program Reviews and Evaluations, and University of Michigan.
  - Archaeological Subject File
    The Archaeological Subject Files and Ceramics Research subseries contain research on a number of different topics in archaeology. Most of these files do not relate to a single archaeological site or project, but rather a geographic area, chronological period, culture, or topic. Of particular note within the Ceramics Research subseries are notes Griffin compiled while researching pottery in the former Soviet Union in 1961.
    - Adena -- Miscellaneous, 1983-1986 (Box 82)
    - Adena Culture -- Survey of Literature, circa 1958-1959 (Box 82)
    - Africa, undated (Box 82)
    - Approximations of Prehistoric Cultural Chronology, circa 1955-1965; 1 oversize volumes (Volume 1)
    - Bristlecone Pine, undated (Box 82)
    - Climatic Change, 1960s; 2 folders (Box 82)
    - Florida Bibliography, undated (Box 82)
    - Florida Prehistory, 1949 (Box 82)
    - Georgia Coast Chronology (J. Caldwell), 1942 (Box 82)
    - Glacial Lake Agassiz, 1967 (Box 82)
    - Great Lakes and North Sea Post-Glacial Sequence, 1961-? (Box 82)
    - Illinois Bluff Focus Trait List (P. Titterington), 1949 (Box 82)
    - Interpretation of Delaware Prehistory (R. MacNeish), 1951 (Box 82)
    - Iowa, undated (Box 82)
    - Kincaid Trait List, 1937-1943 (Box 82)
    - Koster Archaic, 1970-1977 (Box 82)
    - Mesoamerica, undated (Box 82)
    - Mesoamerica, circa 1950-1969 (Box 82)
    - Middle American Chronology Charts, undated (Box 83)
    - Mississippi Chronology (J. Jennings), 1942 (Box 83)
    - North Carolina, circa 1959 (Box 83)
    - Northwest Mexico and Southwest, 1950s
      (Returned to Museum of Anthropology in 2013)
    - Notes on Florida Archaeology (J. Griffin and B. Parsons), undated
    - Notes on Texas Archaeology (A. Krieger), 1942; 2 folders (Box 83)
    - Oklahoma Cultures (D. Baerreis), 1942 (Box 83)
    - Oneota Physical Types (E. Glenn), 1971 (Box 83)
    - Walum Olum, 1954-1955 (Box 83)
  - Ceramic Research
    - Analysis of Woodland Sherds from the Clear Lake Site, 1941
    - Blue Is, undated
    - Buffalo Museum Middle Mississippi Pottery Identification Data (includes photos), 1937
    - Ceramic Remains from the King Site, Wycliffe, Kentucky, undated
    - Ceramic Sequence, Anna-Emerald (Cotter), 1950
    - Ceramic Sequence in Powell Tract, Cahokia, 1968
    - Chadron Cord Marked, undated
    - Eskimo Pottery and Northeast Asia, 1950s
    - Fulton Collection from the Bellevue Mound, Louisiana, 1951
    - Iroquois Ceramic Studies, 1947
    - King Mound Pottery, undated
    - Kuhne Site, 1958
    - Marion County Sherds, 1937
    - Mexican Ceramics, undated
    - Mill Creek Culture, undated
    - Mississippi Monks Mound Aspect, undated
    - Missouri Resources Museum Pottery, 1940-1946
    - Monks Mound Pottery Types, undated
    - Oneota Pottery -- Iowa, 1940-1952
    - Oneota Pottery -- Wisconsin, 1939
    - Prehistoric Pottery, Eastern United States, undated
      (includes photograph)
    - Portsmouth Mound Group (Greenup County, Kentucky) Reel Shape Gorget, undated
    - Possible Antecedents of the Middle Mississippian Ceramic Complex in Northeastern Arkansas, 1940
    - Pottery Analysis and Classifications, 1935-1940
    - Pottery from Douglas County, Illinois, 1943
    - Pottery from Pere Marquette State Park, undated
      (includes photographs)
    - Pottery from the Brandon Site, Minnehaha County, South Dakota, 1941
    - Pottery Remains from the C.H. Knight Mound Group, 1943
    - Pottery Terminology, 1941; undated
    - Pottery Type Analysis, 1959-1960
    - Pottery Type Percentages, undated
    - Principles of Pottery Study, undated
    - Russian and Siberian Ceramics
      - Background Research, 3 folders (Box 84)
      - Notes, 1 folders (Box 84)
      - Photographs, 1 folders (Box 84)
      - Photographs and Negatives, 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Site List, 1955 (Box 84)
      - Translation of Russian Articles on Eurasian Prehistory Project, 1956 (Box 84)
    - Sanders Site Pottery, 1941 (Box 84)
      (comments on A. Krieger's analysis)
    - Seip Mound (includes sample), 1941
    - Sherds from the McFate Site, Erie County, Pennsylvania, 1939
    - South American Ceramics (S. Linn) (Box 84)
      (notes on 1925 publication)
    - Survey of Pottery Types, 1940-1947
    - Technology, 1935-1938
    - Zorn Punctate Ceramics, Ohio River Falls, 1991 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, undated (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 84)
  - Consulting
    The Consulting subseries relates to consulting work Griffin performed mainly after his retirement, including work on museum exhibits, television programs, and archaeological projects.
    - Art of the First Americans Exhibit -- Cincinnati Art Museum, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 84)
      (2 of 5 folders)
    - Art of the First Americans Exhibit -- Cincinnati Art Museum, 1975-1976; 3 folders (Box 85)
      (3 of 5 folders)
    - Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area, 1986 (Box 85)
    - Educational Expeditions International, 1974-1975 (Box 85)
      (re: proposed television program "The Peopling of the New World)
    - Maryland Geological Survey, 1988-1991; 2 folders (Box 85)
    - Nova, circa 1976 (Box 85)
    - Odyssey Television Program on "Mound Builders,", 1979 (Box 85)
    - Ohio's Native American Heritage Exhibit Program, Ohio Historical Center, 1981 (Box 85)
    - Pathways Before Columbus Exhibit, Peabody Museum, Harvard, 1989 (Box 85)
    - Richard B. Russell Dam and Lake Project Area, 1980 (Box 85)
    - Society of Professional Archeologists Peer Review Contract, 1978-1979 (Box 85)
  - Grant Proposals and Projects
    The Grant Proposals and Projects subseries consists of material relating to grant proposals with which Griffin was involved, either as an administrator or a reviewer.
    - University of Michigan
      - National Science Foundation